Guide to the Edwin R. Hoskins papers, [ca.1911-1962].
Hoskins, Edwin R. papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Edwin R. Hoskins papers, [ca.1911-1962].
21-32-1007
Edwin Raymond, Hoskins, 1891-1982.
3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Printed Materials, Publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers concerning administration and supervision of agricultural education; agricultural education curricula; education of teachers; farming programs; agricultural education in secondary schools; institutional on-farm training; and other aspects of agricultural education. Includes reports, surveys, and studies; bulletins; pamphlets; photographs; lectures; corespondence; and other papers.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Edwin Raymond Hoskins (Cornell University Class of 1919, M.S. 1924, Ph.D. 1933) was Professor of Rural Education, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers concerning administration and supervision of agricultural education; agricultural education curricula; education of teachers; farming programs; agricultural education in secondary schools; institutional on-farm training; and other aspects of agricultural education. Includes reports, surveys, and studies; bulletins; pamphlets; photographs; lectures; corespondence; and other papers.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hoskins, Edwin Raymond, 1891-1982.; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Cornell University
Subjects:
Agriculture.; Agricultural education.; College teachers -- Ithaca.; Agricultural education; Agriculture; College teachers; Universities and colleges -- Faculty
Places:
New York (State) -- Ithaca
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Section A. Administration and Supervision of Agricultural Education
Section B. Basic Surveys and Studies (Research)
Section C
Section D
Section E. Education of Teachers (Practice Teaching and Apprentice Training)
Section F. Education of Teachers (Practice Teaching and Apprentice Training)
Section G: Guidance and Ninth Grade Agriculture
H-I: Historic Documents
H-II: Historic Documents
Section I. Institutional On-Farm Training
Section XYZ-I: Out of School Youth (Young Farmers)
Section XYZ-II: Adult Education
CONTAINER LIST
- Section A. Administration and Supervision of Agricultural Education, 1927-1954
  - Reports and Other Materials of Instruction: Rural Education Department, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Topical Outline for State Plan and detailed outline (mimeo. and carbon, respectively)
  - Reports and Other Materials of Instruction, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Certificates for administrative supervisory service and certificates for school service, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Printed matter published by the University of the State of N.Y. (5 items)
  - Executive officers and state directors of vocational education, 1946; Federal Security Agency (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - State supervisors of occupational information and guidance, 1946; Federal Security Agency (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agricultural teacher trainees, 1949; Federal Security Agency (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - State supervisors of agricultural education, 1949; Federal Security Agency (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Objectives for Vocational Agriculture in the State of Delaware for the year 1932-1933, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Mimeograph
  - State Directory, July 15, 1946, and Oct. 10, 1946, 1946-07-15-1946-10-10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Outline of activities of interest to teachers of vocational education in N.Y., 1948-1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Program of 35th Annual Regional Conference on Agricultural Education, North Atlantic Region, 1954-04-20-1954-04-23 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Summary report from North Atlantic Education Workshop, 1954-08-16-1954-08-18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Agricultural Series (Bulletin #115, April 1927), 1927-04 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Report of National Committee
  - Vocational Education (Bulletin #1; Rev. 1948), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Regarding Federal Acts
  - Correspondence from the University of the State of N.Y., 1945-10-23; Tremper, Anne B.; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Correspondence from State Education Dept. Asst, Commissioner for Teacher Education Anne B. Tremper to Prof. Hoskins
  - Printed list of qualifications required of teachers in rural secondary schools of N.Y. State, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter to faculty of School of Education re: Superintendent's Certificate, 1945-12-21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Copy of N. Y. application for teacher's certificate, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Vocational Division Monograph #21, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - University of State of N.Y. Bulletin #1292, 1362, 1363, 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Handbook #41, 1948-10; University of the State of New York (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - University of the State of N.Y. Bulletin re: certification, 1934-1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Supervisory Letters (to first-year teachers), 1939-03-1939-05 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Contains letters to J.W. Hatch (Mar. 17, 1939), W.J. Weaver (Apr. 27, 1939), and R.C.S. Sutliff (May 17, 1939)
  - Summary by E. C. Lattimore of points mentioned in 35 supervisory letters to first-year teachers of vocational agriculture in N.Y., 1938-1939; Lattimore, E.C. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    2 mimeographs
  - Analysis of reports of N.Y. State supervisors of vocational agriculture to high school principals, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Section B. Basic Surveys and Studies (Research), 1941-1954
  - Vocational Education Bulletin 188: "Young Men in Farming.", Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Masters' and Doctors' Theses bibliography, Cornell University Library., Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Young Men in Teaching", 1944; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1950-03-23-1950-05-25 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dennis, L.H.
  - 1951-01-15-1952-07-10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Mobley, M.D.
  - Operating policies for AVA pamphlet, 1952-12 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1953-01-09-1954-02-15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Mobley, M.D.
  - AVA Membership Record (1950-51) and Research Report (Nov. 27, 1951), 1950-1951-11-27 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter to AVA members, 1952-01-21; Schmidt, Harry C. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bulletin 825 of Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station: "Planning Programs for Veterans", 1945-11; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Printed
  - "Planning Programs and Individual Services for Veterans in Rural Areas" and "Reeducation in Rural Areas.", Date Unknown; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Typed papers
  - Progress Report re: research in the education of farm veterans, 1950; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Education of Veterans in Farming", 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Summation of AVA Bulletin #5 by E. R. Hoskins
  - Sample of Schedules A, B and C for N.Y. re: veterans in farming, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Workshop Summer Session: Reprint from "Curriculum Journal," Vol. 13, #1, (Jan. 1942), 1941-11-01-1942-01; Spreight, Harold (Box 1, Folder 13)
    A School Faculty at a Summer Workshop (with a confidential letter to Hoskins from Harold Speight, dated Nov. 1, 1941)
  - Cornell Workshop Summer Session: Memorandum of plans and materials relating to education conferences during the spring of 1941, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Workshop Summer Session: Opening lecture of workshop, 1941-07-09; Spreight, Harold (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Workshop Summer Session: Miscellaneous correspondence re: planning of workshop session, 1941-01 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Workshop Summer Session: Curriculum, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Workshop Summer Session: Miscellaneous correspondence re: staff meetings, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hoskins, Edwin R.
  - Cornell Workshop Summer Session: Material on integration of various subjects (e.g., mathematics, home economics, etc.) with vocational agriculture, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Workshop Summer Session: Evaluative material re: workshop, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Workshop Summer Session: Bibliography, 1941-08-23; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Includes letter from Prof. Hoskins to members of program
  - Cornell Workshop Summer Session: Report of the Agricultural Group of the Workshop Summer Session, 1941, 1941; Harrington, Ray (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Workshop -- 1949 Summer Session: Miscellaneous information re: curriculum, bibliography and workers, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Workshop -- 1949 Summer Session: Paper on exchange of classes between agriculture and homemaking departments, 1949; Sheldon, E. Vail (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Workshop -- 1949 Summer Session: Long-Time Program Teaching Plan by two Texas teachers, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Workshop -- 1949 Summer Session: List of projects produced by members of workshop, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Material re: 10-hour unit of instruction, 1942-1943, 1941-06-1943 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Includes correspondence and an abstract from the thesis of Russell D. Martin, June 1941
  - 1945-10-15 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hoskins, Edwin R., New York State Council on Rural Education
  - 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hoskins, Edwin R.
    Approximately 3 full carbon copies -- not complete sets
  - 1950-10 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Section C, 1931-1958
  - Report on "Young Men in Farming", 1939-1940; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Original copy
  - Curriculum objectives, 1949; Farnum, William; Huxtable, James (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Curriculum objectives, especially F. W. Lathrop's X-section method of course organization called Horizontal Plan in N.Y. as based upon the evaluation of Area Resources. Also, similar papers by William Farnum and James Huxtable, 1949
  - A study of course offerings and organization in 41 schools, 1938; Barnum, William; Curtis, Chester; Hedges, Frank; McWilliams, Leonard (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Area Resources and Course Offerings -- I. 3 departments of Vocational Agriculture (R. E. 237): Homer Central School, 1946; Sidney, Howard (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Typed
  - Area Resources and Course Offerings -- I. 3 departments of Vocational Agriculture (R. E. 237): Near Peru, 1946; Mulbury, M.F (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Area Resources and Course Offerings -- II. Trumansburg Central School, 1946; Green, J. Paul (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Area Resources and Course Offerings -- II. Newark Valley, 1946; Alexander, Donald (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Area Resources and Course Offerings -- II. Albion High School, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Typed mimeograph and carbon copy
  - Area Resources and Course Offerings -- III. Jamesville High School, 1946; Bishop, Frank (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Area Resources and Course Offerings -- III. Franklin Central School, 1946; Lattin, G.E. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Area Resources and Course Offerings -- III. Ithaca High School, 1946; Preston, L.A. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1931-11-01 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Getman, Arthur, Weaver, W.J.
  - 1942-1949 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Curriculum in Extension Education -- Poona Agricultural College", 1958-01; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Section D, 1941-1949
  - Evaluation of programs: Printed booklet re: evaluative criteria for vocational education in agriculture, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Evaluation of programs: 31 local N. Y. State Programs evaluated, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Instructional outlines, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Several copies
  - Outline sheets for use in program planning, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 5 local N.Y. State programs: Fillmore, Date Unknown; Sherman, Bill (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 5 local N.Y. State programs: Sauquoit Valley, 1948-1949; Grubel, Leonard C. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 5 local N.Y. State programs: Ithaca, 1941-1942; Mack, J.A.; Rich, F.A. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 5 local N.Y. State programs: Letchworth, 1947-1948; Robinson, Donald (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 5 local N.Y. State programs: Cazenovia, Date Unknown; Hatch, J.W. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Five student re-evaluations of standards (term papers), Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Section F. Education of Teachers (Practice Teaching and Apprentice Training), 1917-1957
  - Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1933-1937 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Practice centers -- teaching plans, 1932-1943 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1917-1950 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Hoskins, Edwin R.
  - Future Farmers of America Programs, 1941-1955 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Five-year plan assignments to departments, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Apprentice teaching in 4 areas -- regulations. Paper: "Apprentice Teaching Program in Agricultural Education," by Prof. Hoskins, 1950; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Area II -- Placement tour, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Apprentice training -- Area III: "The Organization and Direction of Young Farmers", Date Unknown; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bulletins: University of the State of N.Y., 1945-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Bulletins: University of the State of N.Y., 1949-03-01 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 1949-09 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 1954 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Section E. Education of Teachers (Practice Teaching and Apprentice Training), 1920-1954
  - Instructional Materials: "Developing Long-time Project Plans from Units of Instruction.", Date Unknown; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Mimeographed paper
  - Instructional Materials: "Big Plans for Farming", Date Unknown; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - University of the State of New York
  - Forms for reporting supervised farming, 1920-1949 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Record Books I: "Financing N.Y. Farm Business", 1936-08; Sutliff, R.C.S.; Ham, Peter (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Record Books I: Farm Study Manual, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Record Books I: Vocational Agricultural Guidebook, 1943-04-10 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Prof. Hoskins wrote a letter which aided in the revision of the guidebook, copy dated Apr. 10, 1943
  - Record Books II: Teacher's Handbook - Vocational Agriculture, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Record Books II: My Training Program in Vocational Agriculture, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Distributed by the Mississippi Association of FFA
  - Record Books III: "Guiding High School Students" booklet (Voc. Dev. Bul. #254), Date Unknown; Johnson, E.J.; Elam, W.N. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Record Books III: Supervised Farming Programs in Vocational Agriculture, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Record Books III: "My Training Program", Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 42)
    A blank record book -- no entries filled in
  - Record Books II: "Preparation and Use of Teaching Aids in Agriculture" pamphlet, Date Unknown; Noakes, Harold L.; 100 pages. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Manuscript pamphlet
  - Summaries from 8 departments: Supervised farming reports, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Summaries from 8 departments: State reports of all departments, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Establishment of Approved Farm Practices, Date Unknown; Power, R.A. (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Printed material
  - State evaluation of all departments, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Term papers on supervised farming, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Term papers on supervised farming, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Section G: Guidance and Ninth Grade Agriculture, 1928-1952
  - Two courses of study in pre-vocational agriculture: Homer Central and Marlborough Central Schools, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Area studies: Peru, Date Unknown (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Area studies: Dryden, Date Unknown (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Area studies: Penn Yan, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Includes a 1941 publication from the General Educational Board re: a 7th grade situation
  - Pre-vocational emphasis: Outline of courses prepared during a Cornell Summer Session, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Pre-vocational emphasis: Miscellaneous plans proposed by teachers for selected units in pre-vocational agriculture, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Articles by Arthur K. Getman, Date Unknown; Getman, Arthur K. (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Bibliography on youth problems, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Surveys of youth problems, Oneonta, Van Hornesville, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Letter from George Works, 1928-11-14; Works, George (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Industrial Arts Emphasis, 1932-1938 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    Miscellaneous printed material on industrial arts programs in junior high school, 1932 and 1938
  - Bulletins, 1942-1949 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    Miscellaneous pamphlets re advantages of agriculture as a vocation -- study of in junior high school
  - Date Unknown (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Term paper for R.E. 230, 1952-07-25 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    An outline of trends in facilities through the decades
- H-I: Historic Documents, 1932-1954
  - AVA Bulletin, 1944-03 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    Major contributions by R.M. Stewart
  - Information and picture from R.M. Stewart's 50th wedding anniversary, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Various articles on agricultural education, 1943-1948; Stewart, R.M. (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Report, 1946; Morrison, J.C.; Crane, Edmund H. (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Writings and reports by certain staff members, Date Unknown; Winsor, A.L.; Butterworth, J.E.; Elliott, L.H.; Woodruff, A.D.; Anderson, W.A. (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - "Whither Agricultural Education?" pamphlet, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    Contains article "Building Attitudes" by Dr. Paul J. Kruse, Prof. of Psychology, C.U., pp. 11-18
  - Photographs, 1932-1962 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    Contains: Two 3 1/2" x 5" photographs of Dr. Kruse, 1945, 1962; 8" x 10" photograph of Geo. A. Works, founder of the Dept. of Rural Education, N.Y.S. College of Agric., C.U., undated; 3 1/3" x 4 1/2" photograph of Prof. Emery N. Ferriss, 1932; 3 3/4" x 2 1/2" photograph of Prof. Ferriss with his family, undated
  - Writings and reports by graduate students and letter to Prof. Hoskins, 1949-08-30 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Date Unknown (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Hoskins, Edwin R.
  - Reports and articles, Date Unknown; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 2, Folder 60)
    Mimeograph and carbon copies
  - Published and printed articles, Date Unknown; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 2, Folder 61)
- H-II: Historic Documents, 1911-1955
  - Bulletins and announcements prior to 1917, Date Unknown (Box 2, Folder 62)
    Includes bulletins and announcements from such schools as Belleville, Chautauqua, Albion, etc.
  - Association of Teachers of Agriculture Conference, 1940-1950 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Lists of teachers of agriculture of N.Y., 1930-1943 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Lists of teachers of agriculture of N.Y., 1943-1955 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Agricultural Teachers Bulletin, 1919-1924, 1919-1924 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    Incomplete set
  - Agricultural Teachers Bulletin, 1924-1931, 1924-1931 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - The Record - The Association of Teachers of Agriculture, 1911-1961; 4 volumes (Box 2)
    1911-1931, 1911-1941, 1911-1951, 1911-1961
- Section I. Institutional On-Farm Training, 1940-1953
  - N.Y. State course outlines and course outlines prepared as term project by student, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Term paper regarding research in veterans' education, 1953; Coffin, Robert (Box 3, Folder 69)
    Term paper by a student of Prof. Hoskins in R.E. 234
  - Local programs of institutional on-the-farm training (Ovid, Winfield, etc.), Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Federal Committees on Research regarding farm veterans, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Bulletins from Arkansas, Washington, and Missouri regarding institutional on-farm training, 1950-1953 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Visual aids used extensively in Mississippi: Letter to Hoskins from O.R. Snowden, 1952-07-25; Snowden, O.R. (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Visual aids used extensively in Mississippi: Film catalog from Mississippi State College plus miscellaneous forms, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - State regulations, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Material on "Farm and Home Week", 1942 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    Correspondence to and from Hoskins regarding the plans for Farm and Home Week
  - Federal regulations regarding food production, war training, etc., in forms, programs and printed pamphlet, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Report on farm training for war veterans, 1952-12; Coffin, Robert (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Paper on farm training for war veterans, Date Unknown; Shotwell, Allen (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Wartime activities in N.Y. schools: Statistical summary, 1940-1944 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Wartime activities in N.Y. schools: Photographs (Ovid, Randolph, West Leyden), 1940-1944 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Wartime activity in 6 N.Y. state schools: Naples, Holland, Moravia, Spencer, Union Springs, Ithaca, 1940-1944 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    Photographs for Ithaca only
- Section XYZ-I: Out of School Youth (Young Farmers), 1938-1955
  - Course outlines, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Bibliography, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Population survey, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Instructional materials, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 80)
    Miscellaneous printed, mimeo., and typed materials -- some information regarding Cornell Conference
  - Farm status establishment in farming, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Cornell Extension Bulletin #679: "Getting Started in Poultry Farming," by Darrah and Bruckner, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Placement tours in cooperation with Dr. Stanley Warren, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 82)
    Mimeograph and typed materials regarding student tours; 2 photos included
  - N.Y. State Programs, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    Mimeographed materials and short letter (copy) from Prof. Hoskins
  - Early Programs of "Young Farmers" at Trumansburg, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 84)
    Includes some correspondence to and from Hoskins
  - Term projects, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Term projects, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Term projects, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Miscellaneous references, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 88)
    Includes "Case Study of 14 Young Farmer Programs"
- Section XYZ-II: Adult Education, 1935-1953
  - Instructional materialS, Date Unknown; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 3, Folder 89)
    Includes carbon copy of Prof. Hoskins' "Certain Contributions to Adult Education"
  - Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Panels and conferences: Miscellaneous, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 91)
    Miscellaneous printed and mimeo. material re: the merits of panel discussions in agriculture and other adult educational fields (some outlines from Prof. Hoskins' classes and student critiques)
  - Panels and conferences: "Suggestions and Procedure for a Panel Discussion", Date Unknown; Hoskins, Edwin R. (Box 3, Folder 91)
    Carbon copy
  - Forums, 1940-1953 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    Miscellaneous printed and mimeographed material re: formation and procedure of forums
  - Discussion group and topic outlines as carried at Kings Ferry, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Problems for nationwide discussion groups, 1938-10-24-1939-02-19; Wallace, Henry (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Hoskins' associations with the N.Y. State Citizens' Council and the American Association of Adult Education: Brockport State Normal School Summer Institute, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    News clipping re: Hoskins' participation and letter to the professor
  - "Hoskins' associations with the N.Y. State Citizens' Council and the American Association of Adult Education: Bulletins of N.Y. State Citizens' Council, 1945-05-1945-07 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Hoskins' associations with the N.Y. State Citizens' Council and the American Association of Adult Education: Correspondence, 1945-07-1945-08 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    Re: Colgate Conference and Syracuse University Institute
  - Hoskins' associations with the N.Y. State Citizens' Council and the American Association of Adult Education: Correspondence, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 94)